vertu.com 2016-11-25

# Privacy & Cookie Policy | Legal Notices | Vertu

**We care about your privacy.**

Vertu is committed to protecting your privacy and to complying with applicable data protection and privacy laws. Please read this privacy policy (the “Policy”) carefully as it explains how Vertu Corporation Limited ('"we" or "us") and our affiliates use your personal information.

This Policy applies where we refer to this Policy and where we process of your personal data including:

  * On this website [**datacontroller@vertu.com**](mailto:datacontroller@vertu.com);
  * When you make an enquiry to us;
  * Through your Vertu account;
  * When you buy and use our products or services;
  * Through the Vertu apps;
  * When we send you offers, deals and news.

If you have any questions about the Policy or do not agree with it, please contact us at [**datacontroller@vertu.com**](mailto:datacontroller@vertu.com) before using this website or our products and services.

We may change this Policy from time to time by updating this page. If this Policy is changed in a material way that is likely to adversely affect your privacy, we will post a notice advising of such change at the beginning of this Policy and on this site's home page for 30 days. You should check this page from time to time to ensure you are happy with any changes.

**Who are we?**

We are Vertu Corporation Limited and subsidiaries or affiliates (“Vertu”), a company validly organised and existing under the laws of England & Wales, with company number 07753443, having its registered office address at Beacon Hill Road, Church Crookham, Hampshire, GU52 8DY. You can contact us by email at [**datacontroller@vertu.com**](mailto:datacontroller@vertu.com).

In accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998, Vertu is registered as a 'Data Controller' on the public Register of Data Controllers as maintained by the UK’s Information Commissioner.

**What Information do we collect and how do we use it?**

**In general:**

In general, you can use our website without giving us any information. However, please bear in mind that we may still record:

  * the areas of the website that you visit, the duration of your visit, how you entered the website; and
  * information about your device, such as which browser you are using, your network location, the type of connection you are using (e.g. broadband, ADSL etc.).
  * information about your use of our website if you have visited from Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn or other third party platforms/websites. All data collected is totally anonymous, and is used to create tailored messaging specific to your interests on these platforms/websites

We gather this information using cookies – see the cookies section below for more information.

We use this information for internal record keeping and improving our products and services.

**Specific data collection:**

We collect, or you may give us, specific information about you in the following situations:

  * **On the website**

You may choose to provide us with information about yourself when you use the website if you want to contact a boutique, receive our newsletter and update emails, or if you contact us. If you do this we will use your information only for the purpose for which it was provided. For more detail on our marketing policy, see the Marketing section below.

  * **Device Registration, purchases and interactions**

We collect information relating to you and your purchase and use of our products and services and those of our partners and your other interactions with us. Such information may include device registration details, details of the queries or requests you have made, where, when and how they were made, the products and services purchased or provided, delivery details, bank account number, credit card details, billing address, credit checks and other such financial information, details of agreements between you and us, records of contacts and communications, information and details relating to the content you have provided us with and other such transactional information. We may, in accordance with applicable law, record your communications with our customer services operation or with other such contact points including Vertu Concierge service and by any channel offered including but not limited to telephone, SMS, email or live chat.

This information is required in order to actually deliver our services and administer your account. We may also use this information to improve our products and services.

Some of our apps also require location based information to provide their service. For example when you make a location-based search, use location-enhanced weather features or request map data, your location data may be sent to us to serve you with the right content. This may also include location-based advertising within the app.

Some location-based services may allow you to associate your personal data with your location. Location-based services and features may use satellite, mobile, WiFi or other network-based positioning methods which may involve exchanging your location data, network identifiers and your unique device identifiers with a location server.

Depending on your positioning settings and your use of location services of other service providers, your device may connect to other service providers’ servers, which are not controlled or operated by us. We recommend you check the privacy policies of such service providers to understand how they process your location data. You can modify the positioning settings of your device from the device settings, for example change or disable positioning methods or location servers or modify the accuracy of your location data.

  * **List rental**

We may also obtain, in accordance with applicable law, some personal data from list-rental companies or from publicly available sources. We may use this information to send you marketing that you may find interesting. See the 'General Marketing' section below for further details on our marketing.

**General Marketing**

We would like to provide you with information about Vertu’s products and services and those offered by its group companies, as well as other information about products and services from our partner and affiliate organisations which we think you may find interesting.

Where you have requested to receive information from us, or if you are a customer of ours or you have previously asked us for information on our products and services, we may send you such information by post, email and/or telephone unless you have asked us not to do so.

Some of the Vertu Apps also deliver marketing that we believe you may find interesting. If you no longer wish to receive those messages, you should no longer use the relevant app.

We don't provide your personal information to external organisations (i.e. outside of the Vertu group) for their own marketing purposes without your explicit consent.

If at any time you do not want your information used for direct marketing purposes please either follow the unsubscribe link in one of our marketing email messages or contact us at [**customer.service@vertu.com**](mailto:customer.service@vertu.com).

**Do we share personal data?**

We do not sell, lease, or rent your personal data to third parties. However we may share where we have your consent to do so, or in the following circumstances:

  * **Where legally required to do so**

In some circumstances, we may have to disclose your personal information by law or because a court or the police or other law enforcement agency has asked us for it.

  * **Your consent and social sharing services**

Some services may allow you to share your personal data with other users of the service or with other services and their users. Please consider carefully before disclosing any personal data or other information that might be accessible to other users.

  * **Vertu companies and authorised third parties**

We may share your personal data with other Vertu companies or authorised third parties who process personal data for us for the purposes described in this Policy. This may include, for example, delivery of your purchases, providing services including customer service, managing and analysing consumer data, credit checks, conducting market research and managing marketing and other such campaigns.

We may conduct joint marketing and other communications with our partners. To avoid duplicate or unnecessary communications and to tailor the message to you we may need to match information that we have collected with information that the partner has collected where this is permitted by law.

These authorised third parties are not permitted to use your personal data for any other purposes. We require them to act consistently with this Policy and to use appropriate security measures to protect your personal data.

  * **Mergers and Acquisitions**

If we decide to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganise our businesses in certain countries, this may involve us disclosing personal data to prospective or actual purchasers and their advisers, or receiving personal data from sellers and their advisers.

**International transfers of personal data**

Our products and services may be provided using resources and servers located in various countries around the world. Therefore your personal data may be transferred across international borders outside the country where you use our services, including to countries outside the European Economic Area (EEA) that do not have laws providing specific protection for personal data or that have different legal rules on data protection, for example, the United States of America. In such cases we take steps to ensure that there is a legal basis for such a transfer and that adequate protection for your personal data is provided as required by applicable law, for example, by using standard agreements approved by relevant authorities (where necessary) and by requiring the use of other appropriate technical and organisational information security measures.

**Security: What steps are taken to safeguard your information?**

Privacy and security are key considerations in the creation and delivery of our products and services, including our apps and website. We have assigned specific responsibilities to address privacy- and security-related matters. We enforce our internal policies and guidelines through an appropriate selection of activities, including proactive and reactive risk management, security engineering, training and assessments. We take appropriate steps to address online security, physical security, risk of data loss and other such risks taking into consideration the risk represented by the processing and the nature of the data being protected. Also, we limit access to our data bases containing personal data to authorised persons having a justified need to access such information.

If at any point you suspect or become aware of a security incident (i.e. your password is stolen or you receive suspicious communication from someone holding themselves out to be a Vertu employee or from a dupe website claiming to be affiliated with Vertu), please forward the communication to us or report the incident by contacting [**Vertu Customer Service.**](http://www.vertu.com/global/en/contact-us/)

We keep data for as long as is necessary for the purpose for which we obtained it and in accordance with our data retention policies. Once it is no longer required, your data will be securely destroyed.

**What are your rights?**

You have a right to know what personal data we hold about you.

You have a right to have incomplete, incorrect, unnecessary or outdated personal data deleted or updated.

You have a right to unsubscribe from marketing messages and to request that we stop processing your personal data for direct marketing or market research purposes. However, if you opt out from receiving marketing and other communications from us and our affiliates and partners, we may still send you critical alerts pertaining to our products and services or contact you for these purposes.

**How to get copies of or amend the information we have collected**

You may request details of the personal information that we hold about you under data protection laws. If you would like a copy of the information held about you, please write to us at Vertu Corporation Limited, of Beacon Hill Road, Church Crookham, Hampshire, GU52 8DY or email us at [**datacontroller@vertu.com**](mailto:datacontroller@vertu.com). A small fee (up to £10) will be charged for providing copies of personal information

If you think any information we have about you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to us or email us as soon as possible. We will correct or update any information as soon as we can.

We encourage you to use available profile management tools, for example your Vertu Account which provides you with direct access to your personal data and allows you to effectively manage it.

**Cookies**

When you use our website, or when you “Register My Handset” or use our services and apps on your handset, we will know who you are and your activities on this website and information about you and/or your company may be recorded on our systems. We do this using cookies. Cookies also help us to improve your experience of our website and to ensure that it performs as you expect it to.

Cookies are text files containing small amounts of information, which are downloaded to your computer or mobile device by websites that you visit. They can improve your experience of using a website, for example by remembering your preference settings and tracking your use of a website so that it can be improved to meet your needs.

In some instances, websites must now get consent to send cookies to your computer or mobile device.

You can set your cookie preferences when you arrive at our website, or change them at any time by changing the security settings in your web browser.

You can withdraw your consent to our cookies at any time even if you have previously consented. Although, please do remember that if you do not consent to our analytical and strictly necessary cookies, parts of our website or app, including Live Agent Chat, may not work. For example, you will not be able to watch our videos or you will not be able to log into your Vertu Account. For this reason we will occasionally send you prompts which allow you to consent to a cookie you have previously rejected.

We explain below what cookies we use on our website and apps, why we use them and whether they are strictly necessary or another type of cookie e.g. "functionality" or "performance" cookies. We also state whether a cookie is a "persistent" or "session" cookie. The difference is that:

  * Persistent cookies remain on your device between browsing sessions. They are activated each time you visit the website that created that particular cookie. For example, where a "persistent cookie" is used on a website to remember your log-in details, you will not need to enter those details each time you visit that website.
  * Session cookies allow website operators to link the actions of a user during a browser session. A browser session starts when you open the browser window and finishes when you close the browser window. Session cookies are created temporarily. Once you close the browser, all session cookies are deleted.

**Strictly necessary**

Strictly necessary cookies are essential to enable you to receive a service on a website. For example, cookies to operate the cookie notification itself, enable log-in functionality or to comply with the law (e.g. such as to keep your information safe). We would not be able to operate our website without using the "strictly necessary" cookies listed below.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent/Session | More information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Demandware | dwsecuretoken_xxxxx | Https-session cookie | Session | Demandware  
Demandware | dwanonymous_ xxxxx | Anonymous tracking | 6 months | Demandware  
Demandware | dwsid | DWRE Session cookie | Session | Demandware  
Demandware | dwcustomer_xxxxx | Stores DWRE customer data | 6 months | Demandware  
Demandware | dwsourcecode_xxxxx | Source Code cookie | 24 hours | Demandware  
  
**Analytics**

Analytics cookies collect information about how visitors use a website, for instance, which pages visitors go to most often and if they get error messages from web pages. These cookies do not collect information that identifies a visitor. Any information collected by these cookies is anonymous. We only use such information to improve our website.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent/Session | More information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Google Analytics | _utma  
_utmb  
_utmc  
_utmv  
_utmz | Collect anonymous visitor information¹ | Persistent | [**Click here**](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) for an overview of privacy at Google  
Demandware | dwac_xxxxx | DWRE analytics | Session  
Yandex Analytics | _ym_visorc  
_ym_uid  
_ym_isad | Collect anonymous visitor information¹ | Persistent | [**Click here**](https://yandex.com/legal/confidential/) for an overview of privacy at Yandex  
Baidu Tongji | Hm_lvt | Collect anonymous visitor information¹ | Persistent | [**Click here**](https://www.baidu.com/duty/yinsiquan.html) for an overview of privacy at Baidu  
Crazy Egg | is_returning | Collect anonymous visitor information¹ | 5 Years | [**Click here**](https://www.crazyegg.com/privacy) for an overview of privacy at Crazy Egg  
  
¹These cookies are used to collect anonymous information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile analytical reports which help us improve our website. The cookies collect information such as the number of visitors to our website, how they arrived there (e.g. directly from the internet or through linking from another website) and tracking which webpages they visited.

**Functionality**

Functionality cookies allow the website to remember choices you make (such as your log in details) and customised preference settings (e.g. text size). They also enable enhanced, more personal features, for example a website may be able to provide you with local weather reports or traffic news by using a cookie to remember which region you are in. These cookies are also used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video. Information collected by "functionality" cookies may or may not be anonymised, but they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites. The "functionality" cookies on our website only collect anonymous information.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent/Session | More information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Salesforce - Liveagent | X-Salesforce-eLB | Salesforce Live agent Chat functionality  
Salesforce - Liveagent | liveagent_oref | Salesforce Live agent Chat functionality  
Salesforce - Liveagent | liveagent_ptid | Salesforce Live agent Chat functionality  
Salesforce - Liveagent | liveagent_sid | Salesforce Live agent Chat functionality  
Salesforce - Liveagent | liveagent_vc | Salesforce Live agent Chat functionality  
  
**Targeting**

These cookies collect information about your browsing habits to make advertising relevant to you and your interests. These cookies collect the most information about users.

Cookie | Name | Purpose | Persistent/Session | More information  
---|---|---|---|---  
Demandware | dwpersonalization_xxxxx | Can be used for A/B testing | 31 days  
Demandware | country_data | Stores locale | Persistent  
Facebook | Facebook Pixel Code | Advertising Insights | 28 days  
Twitter | Facebook Pixel Code | Advertising Insights | 90 Days
